Guide to the Paul S. Seaver Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Paul S. Seaver papers
1963-2005
SC0769
Seaver, Paul S.
30 Linear feet
The papers primarily document Seaver's career at Stanford University and include correspondence, class materials, and departmental records. His correspondence files date from 1963-1987 and include one file on conscientious objection to military service. Course files, 1964-2005, include syllabi, exams, course readers, student papers, and course evaluations. There are also materials on traditional Western Civilization courses and on two alternate academic programs - CIV (Cultures, Ideas and Values) and VTSS (Values, Technology, Science and Society); included are syllabi, course proposals, committee records, correspondence, memoranda, student reviews, and clippings, 1966-97. Departmental and professional papers include committee records, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and other materials, 1966-93; included are several folders on a peace studies program on campus.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Paul S. Seaver joined the Stanford faculty in the Dept. of History in 1964; he received the Dean's Award for Excellence in Teaching in 1981 and the Dinkelspiel Award for outstanding service to undergraduate education in 1987. His specialty was early modern English history. He was involved in the efforts to expand the course content of the Western Civilization requirement, serving as head of a task force to review the Western culture program (1986) and as Director of the Program in Cultures, Ideas and Values (1989-92). Seaver earned his Ph.D. at Harvard and started his career as an instructor at Reed College, 1962-64. Raised in the Quaker faith, Seaver refused induction into the Armed Services in 1950 and served 18 months in federal prison.
Description of the Collection
The papers primarily document Seaver's career at Stanford University and include correspondence, class materials, and departmental records. His correspondence files date from 1963-1987 and include one file on conscientious objection to military service. Course files, 1964-2005, include syllabi, exams, course readers, student papers, and course evaluations. There are also materials on traditional Western Civilization courses and on two alternate academic programs - CIV (Cultures, Ideas and Values) and VTSS (Values, Technology, Science and Society); included are syllabi, course proposals, committee records, correspondence, memoranda, student reviews, and clippings, 1966-97. Departmental and professional papers include committee records, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and other materials, 1966-93; included are several folders on a peace studies program on campus.
Access Terms
Seaver, Paul S.; Stanford University. Department of History.; Civilization, Western--Study and teaching.; Conscientious objection.; Great Britain--History--Study and teaching (Higher).; Multicultural education--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, Series 1
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Spring, Summer, Autumn quarters, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Professional) 1 of 3, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Professional) 2 of 3, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Professional) 3 of 3, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence- Autumn/Winter 1 of 2, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- Autumn/Winter 2 of 2, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Spring, Summer, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Autumn 1 of 2, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Autumn 2 of 2, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Spring, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Summer, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1973-1974 Spring (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Spring, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Spring, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Spring, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1977-1978 Winter (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Spring, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Spring/Summer, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Winter and Spring, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Summer/Autumn, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-Winter/Spring, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence-Spring/Summer, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence-Winter/Spring, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Autumn, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Winter/Spring, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Winter, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Clark Library Paper Correspondence, 1974 October (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Studies correspondence and various, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and forms concerning Conscientious Objection, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - H. Friedman, Philosophy, Memoranda and Correspondence, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Overseas Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Overseas Studies, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Overseas Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Society for Religion in Higher Education Newsletters, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Press Conference, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Courses, Series 2
  - History 2: Great Works, Stanford Course Evaluation, Winter, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History 6: Department of History Course Evaluations, Fall, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History 15: Dr. Coffey, Jack; Class Evaluation, Winter, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History 18, Course Evaluations, Fall, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History 42S, London: The Making of the Metropolis, 1 of 2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History 142, Stuart England, 1603-1689, Fall, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History 42S, London: The Making of the Metropolis, 2 of 2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History 100x, Basic Seminar, notes and class materials, Spring, 1 of 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History 100x, Basic Seminar, notes and class materials, Spring, 2 of 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History 100x Basic Seminar, Autumn, 1 of 2, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History 100x Basic Seminar, Autumn, 2 of 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History 101A Colloquium, Causes of the English Revolution, Autumn, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History 101A, Analytical Approaches to an understanding of the English Civil War, Autumn, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History 101A, Undergrad Seminar Reading Lists, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History 141, Reading Lists, Winter, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History 141 Syllabus etc, Winter, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History 141 Yorkist and Tudor England, Autumn, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History 141 Exams, Autumn, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History 141, Exams, Autumn, 1 of 3, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History 141, Exams, Autumn, 2 of 3, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History 141, Exams, Autumn, 3 of 3, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History 141: Tudor England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History 141: Tudor England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - History 141: Tudor England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - History 141: Tudor England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - History 141, Course Evaluations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History 141, Department of History Course Evaluations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - History 142 Exams, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - History 142 Reading Lists, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - History 142, Course Evaluation Experiment, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - History 142, Stuart England, Winter, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History 142: Stuart England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Winter, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - History 142: Stuart England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Winter, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History 142: Stuart England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Winter, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - History 142: Stuart England, Stanford Course Evaluation, Winter, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - History 240, Stanford Course Evaluation, Henry VIII and the English Reformation, Autumn, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - History 240: London: Politics and Culture of Growth, Spring, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - History 241, Spring, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - History 241S Senior Research, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - History 242: Graduate Seminar, Autumn, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - History 242/English 114, English Culture from Moore to Milton, 1 of 3, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - History 242/English 114, English Culture from Moore to Milton, 2 of 3, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History 242/English 114, English Culture from Moore to Milton, 3 of 3, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - History 242: Undergraduate Colloquium, Stanford Course Evaluation, Spring, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History 321, Aspects of social and intellectual change in Tudor and Stuart England, Winter, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History 321 Syllabus, Winter, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - History 321 Bibliography, Syllabus, etc, Spring, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - History 321, Aspects of Social and Intellectual Change, reading lists and bibliographies, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History 321, Graduate Colloquium, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - History 333, Great Reign to Glorious Revolution, Spring, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - History 341, Topics in Tudor and Stuart History, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - History 341: Graduate Colloquium, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - History 341: English Society and Culture, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - History 341: English Society and Culture, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - History 341: Graduate Colloquium, Stanford Course Evaluation, Autumn, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - History 341, Winter, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - History 341, Topics in the History of Early Modern England, Winter, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - History 341 notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - History 341, Winter, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History 342 Graduate Colloquium, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - History 342 Fall, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - History 345D, reading lists, etc, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - History 440, Final Exam notes, Spring, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - History 440, Social and Intellectual Change, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - History 442, 1 of 2, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - History 442, 2 of 2, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Humanities 61: Western Thought and Lit., Course materials and syllabi, Autumn, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - SWOP 115: Conscription, Fall, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - SWOP 165: The Consensus Process. SCIRE project description, Winter, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tudor England: Various Course Syllabi and Reading Lists, 1 of 2, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tudor England: Various Course Syllabi and Reading Lists, 2 of 2, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stuarts and Puritans lecture notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tudor culture and society, Directed Reading, Winter, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - History 141, ASSU Course Guide, Student Questionnaires, Autumn, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - History 141, ASSU Course Evaluation, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - History 141, Yorkist/Tudor England, Course Evaluations, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - History 142, ASSU Course Evaluation, Winter, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - History 142, ASSU Course Evaluation, Winter, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - History 143, England: 1558-1640, Course Evaluations, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - History 240, Growth of London, Course Evaluations, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - History 241, ASSU Course Evaluation, Spring, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - History 341, Early Mod England, Course Evaluations, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - History 442, Grad Seminar, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - History 442, Reading Lists, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Various course reading lists and notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - History 042N, The Invention of Liberty and the English Revolution [Course Reader], Winter, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - History 42N, The Invention of Liberty and the English Revolution [Course Reader], 1640-1660, Winter, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - History 240, Shakespeare's London [Course Reader], Winter, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - History 42N, The Invention of Liberty and the English Revolution [Course Reader], Winter, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - History 240, Early Modern London [Course Reader], Winter, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - History 240, Shakespeare's London [Course Reader], Winter, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - History 042N, The Invention of Liberty and the English Revolution [Course Reader], Spring, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - History 143, Shakespeare's England [Course Reader], 1558-1640, Fall, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - History 042N, The Invention of Liberty and the English Revolution [Course Reader], Spring, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - History 240, Shakespeare's London [Course Reader], Fall, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - History 142, Stuart England, 1603-1689 [Course Reader], Fall, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - History 240, Early Modern London [Course Reader], Spring, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - History 240, Shakespeare's London [Course Reader], Winter, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - History 341, Topics in the History of Early Modern England [Course Reader], Winter, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - History 341B, Topics in the Culture and Society of Early Modern England [Course Reader], Fall, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - History 142, Revolutionary England [Course Reader], Fall, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - History 342, Society and Culture in Early and Modern England, Part B [Course Reader], Spring, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - History 341A, Society and Culture in Early Modern England, Part I [Course Reader], Autumn, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - History 341A, Society and Culture in Early Modern England, Part II [Course Reader], Autumn, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - History 425, London: The Making of the Metropolis [Course Reader], Spring, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - History 342, Society and Culture in Early and Modern England [Course Reader], Spring, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - History 42S, London: The Making of the Metropolis [Course Reader], Spring, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - History 240 [Course Reader], Winter, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - History 141, Yorkist and Tudor England [Course Reader], Fall, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - History 142 [Course Reader], Fall, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - History 141, Yorkist and Tudor England [Course Reader], Fall, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - History 341A, Society and Culture in Early Modern England [Course Reader], Fall, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Vickey Allsup, "The Abyss in Victorian History and Literature," class paper, 1983 July (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - David J. Bycina, "The Elizabethan Episcopal Bench 1558-1580," class paper, 1965 April (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fred H. Cate, "An Introduction to the Life and Thought of Frank Friedman Oppenheimer" [Honors Thesis but not the one he ultimately submitted], 1983 June (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - George S. Craft, "Social Mobility in Buckinghamshire, 1540-1680," class paper, 1967 January (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - George S. Craft, "The County Society of Buckinghamshire, 1540-1680," class paper, 1967 March (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - David Gelb, "The Political Culture of the French Worker under the Fourth Republic," class paper, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mary Goodman, "The Gentry: Rising or Declining?" class paper, 1964 December (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Tracy Grant, "In Honour Bound: The Twilight of the Chivalric Paradigm," Honors Thesis submission, 1968 June (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - James A. Hinz, "Literary Patronage and Puritanism in England, 1560-1640," class paper, 1968 June (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Janice Hough, "A Tudor Tragedy Revisited, Katheryn Howard and her Historians," Honors Thesis submission, 1981 May 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Rex Jones, "The Marriage of Henry VI," class paper, 1976 Winter (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Robert Katz, "Catholic and Puritan in Elizabethan and Stuart England," class paper, 1968 Spring (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Robert Katz, "A Survey of Students at the English College, Rome During the Period 1598-1658," class paper, 1968 October 25 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Ruth Kennedy, "Agriculture and Industry in Oxfordshire and Devonshire Before the Industrial Age," class paper, 1969 June (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Michael K. Lindsay, "Lindsays in Scotland: 1625-1660," class paper, 1968 June (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Howard L. Malchow, "A Demographic Survey of 17th Century Barbados," class paper, 1968 May (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ralph Mann, "Massachusetts Bay and Plymouth: Comparisons of Social Structure and Social Mobility," class paper, 1967 March (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - David Mosler, "The Justices of the Peace of Warwickshire, 1625-1665," class paper, 1976 March (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - George Rainsford, "Henrician Bishops, 1519-1547," class paper, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Gail Stuart Rowe, "Seventeen-Century Harvard Students: A Look at Hierarchy, Placement, and Mobility in New England Society," class paper, 1967 March (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pascale Roy, "King Lear: Brute or Divine Being?" class paper, 1982 Winter (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - John S. Schwarz, S.J., "A Statistical Profile of Emmanuel College, Cambridge, 1585-1699", 1967 March (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Charles L. Stinger, "The Landed Society of Hertfordshire, 1540-1680," class paper, 1967 March 13 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mark Sydow, "'If You Aim at a Scottish Presbytery': The Hampton Court Conference," class paper, 1975 June 5 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Sandralee T. Thomas, "The Episcopal Bench in the Reign of Henry VII, 1485-1509," class paper, 1964 Fall (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Barbara Tinsley, "The Sponges and the Palms: A Study of the Episcopal Bench in the Reign of James I," class paper, Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Robert L. Walker, Jr., "The Edwardine and Marian Episcopacies," class paper, Undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Kenneth B. Wolf, "Parochial Religious Instruction in Medieval and Early Modern England: A Comparative Analysis," Honors Thesis submission, 1978 December (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - "The Social and Geographical Origins of Oxford and Cambridge Students," [no name on paper], Undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
- CIV/Area One, Series 3
  - Western Civilizations material, Closed file, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Book; Syllabus Sources, Stanford History Department, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi and Readings, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Western Civilization Staff business, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Western Civilization current business, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Western Civilization Staff Syllabi, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Western Civilization correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Western Civilization correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Western Civilization correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Western Civilization info to Freshmen, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Western Civilization current business, 1 of 2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Western Civilization current business, 2 of 2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Exams, Etc., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Exams, Etc., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Exams, Etc. 1 of 3, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Exams, Etc. 2 of 3, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Exams, Etc. 3 of 3, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Autumn, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Western Civilization Business, Autumn, 1 of 2, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Western Civilization Business, Autumn, 2 of 2, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Winter, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Spring, 1 of 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Western Civilization Syllabi, Spring, 2 of 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Resource Materials for Western Culture Program, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Task Force on the Area One Requirement, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Area One Task Force, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Syllabus materials, Autumn, 1986; Envelope (Box 5)
  - Western Culture Pilot Program, Undergraduate Education, Autumn, 1986; Envelope (Box 5)
  - Western Culture Program Symposium, Autumn, 1984; Notebook (Box 5)
  - Western Culture Program lectures and notes, Winter, 1983; Notebook (Box 5)
  - CIV Proposed Legislation; Various Newspaper Photocopies, Various Dates, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Area One Requirement and various associated papers; Fall, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Loose papers; Memoranda, Western Culture requirement; Spring, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Syllabi, Reviews, correspondence re: CIV curriculum, 1987 October (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Syllabi, Reviews, correspondence re: CIV curriculum (duplicate copy), 1987 October (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Area One Requirement report and materials on Western Literature and Art, 1987 May-October (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Area One Requirement, CIV proposed legislation, 1987 June-November (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Area One Requirement memoranda and various papers, Spring, 1 of 3, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Area One Requirement memoranda and various papers, Spring, 2 of 3, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Area One Requirement memoranda and various papers, Spring, 3 of 3, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - CIV program proposed legislation and preliminary drafts, 1987-1988; Envelope (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Area One requirement, CIV program proposed legislation, Autumn, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Area One Task Force, Committee Correspondence and memoranda, Winter, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - CIV Materials, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - CIV (Cultures, Ideas, and Values) Correspondence 1 of 2, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - CIV (Cultures, Ideas, and Values) Correspondence 2 of 2, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - CIV materials, Part I of course MC 2024, Autumn, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - CIV, articles and correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - CIV Binder; materials, legislation, proposals, student reviews, 1 of 3, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - CIV Binder; materials, legislation, proposals, student reviews, 2 of 3, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - CIV Binder; materials, legislation, proposals, student reviews, 3 of 3, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - CIV, readings and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)